The fate of the nation rests on the courage of one man.
Air Force One is a action, thriller film directed by Wolfgang Petersen.
When Russian neo-nationalists hijack Air Force One, the world's most secure and extraordinary aircraft, the President is faced with a nearly
impossible decision to give in to terrorist demands or sacrifice not only the country's dignity, but the lives of his wife and daughter.
James Marshall, played by Harrison Ford.
Ivan Korshunov, played by Gary Oldman.
Kathryn Bennett, played by Glenn Close.
Grace Marshall, played by Wendy Crewson.
Alice Marshall, played by Liesel Matthews.
Lloyd Shepherd, played by Paul Guilfoyle.
Air Force One is a 1997 American political action thriller film directed and
co-produced by Wolfgang Petersen and written by Andrew W.
Starring Harrison Ford, Gary Oldman, Glenn Close, Wendy
Crewson, Xander Berkeley, William H.
Macy, Dean Stockwell, Paul Guilfoyle and Jürgen Prochnow, the film follows Air Force One being hijacked by a group of terrorists who demand the
release of their country's imprisoned dictator and the president's attempt to rescue everyone on board by retaking his plane.
The film was a box office success and received mostly positive critical reviews.
It became the fifth highest-grossing film of 1997,
earning $315.2 million worldwide.
It also received two Academy Award nominations for Best Sound and
Best Film Editing, losing both awards to Titanic.
The film explores themes of vietnam veteran, journalist,
usa president, washington dc, usa, airplane.
The tone is intense.